

# Mohammed Rawhani

Web Developer

◆ Sana'a, Cairo ST., Yemen

# ♣ Profile

Energetic hardworking and results-oriented web developer with considerable training and experience in Web site development in all stages of design, coding, and manipulating of Web applications, creating and maintaining functional, attractive, and responsive websites. Clear understanding of modern technologies and best design practices. Experienced with Html, Css, React, NodeJs and databases. Great attention to details and focus on raising UX scores and customer retention.

# Objective

To obtain a position as a web application developer in a fun, fast paced, cutting edge environment that promotes teamwork and integrity and that fosters personal and professional development.

# Employment History

## FullStack developer as a freelancer

September 2019 - Current

- Designing, building, project managing and maintaining websites and web services.
- Focused on using modern technologies such as NodeJs, Mongoose, ExpressJs and best coding and structure practices like OOP and MVC.
- Worked in advanced React with redux, web services, cloud services (AWS).
- · Worked with SVGs and Material UI.

# Web Developer Intern at Grand Technology, Egypt

June 2019 - September 2019

Grand Technology is a global Entertainment company that has taken place in +50 countries. As a web developer, my core activities included:

- Planning site designs, functionality and navigation, along with audience funnels and data capture points.
- Building wireframes & prototypes which were then turned into functional and responsive digital products.
- Reviewing UX with multiple teams and making necessary edits to accommodate technical or business concerns.
- Extracting requiremnts from customers and convert them into digital workarounds.
- Built three websites with deferent functionalities and using variety of tools.
- Used React, Html5, Css3, bootstrap, jquery, sass, and ajax.
- Used .Net Core and MySql for the backend services.
- Used SVN and Github.
- Developed Sites contents and proposals.

#### Details

Cairo ST, Sana'a, Yemen +967-775-600067 mohammedrawhani@gmail.com qithub.com@mrawhani

NATIONALITY

Yemeni

#### Skills

React, Html5, Css3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ES6, Restful Apis,

NodeJs, Mongoose, MongoDB, Web services, MVC.

Wordpress, Gulp, Webpack, NPM, Git and github

Command Line, Windows, Visual Studio .Net, Windows Form, C#, Java, JDBC, C++, Oracle, SQL, OOP,

#### Language

Arabic (Native)

English (Excellent)

French (Basic)

# Employment History (Continued)

## FrontEnd developer as a freelancer

Jan 2019 - June 2019

- · Designing, building, and maintaining websites and landing pages.
- · Focused on using so many modern technologies and best coding and structure practices
- Used Preprocessors, webpack, npm, gulp, advanced css and many more.
- · Used React, Html, Css, Jquery.

### Digital Marketing Strategist as Freelancer

2018 - current

- Developed digital media strategies for 3 companies such as Madinat Sanaa, Alam Aljeans and Malek Aljean. Including content writing, social media ads, and targeting.
- Managed a network of (5) vendors and maintained a good communication between vendors and clients.

### Wedding Planning supervisor at Madinat Sanaa Company

August 2017 - Jan 2019

- A huge step in improving my soft skills; with 10 hours a day of planning, consulting, solving problems, leading, communicating, and marketing.
- Managed a team of 65 employee and distributed the daily task.

### ESL Teacher at Majestic Ins. And Union Collage (Part time job)

2016 - 2018

# Education & Certifications

UST University - Sana'a, Yemen

### Pursuing Bachelor of Computer Science in Software Engineering.

Academic Honors: Computing faculty Top #1 student. (5 semesters).

#### Alnahdah High School – Sana'a, Yemen

• With a high degree of 96%. Achieved me the #5 top of my school and one of the top 30 of the Republic.

## Yemen American Language Institute – Sana'a, Yemen

A 2016 English Language Graduate with a TOEFL ITP certification.

#### Udemy, Plusright, Durga, other platforms – Onilne

 Has done so many online courses in programing, software, web development, digital marketing and many more.

## Various Participating and Certifications

 Has volunteered and participated in many workshops and activities in different interests and fields. With some recognized certifications.